BASTIAAN QUAST PHD HTTPS://BASTIAANQUAST.COM/ | BQUAST@GMAIL.COM

Author of transformer, attention, rnn, HomomorphicEncryption, and HEtools software libraries in R, Python, and Julia. Author of "Transformers from Scratch in R" (forthcoming). Experienced developer in SQL, C, Python (TensorFlow, PyTorch), R, Go, JavaScript.

Employment

2024-	OWNER VALIQ SECURITY, ZURICH, SWITZERLAND Build FHE libraries in Python, Julia, R, C, Rust. Build Swift apps (iOS, MacOS).
2023-24	ML ENGINEER BILLTRUST, NEW JERSEY, USA ML engineer: deep learning, machine learning, Bayesian statistics, data engineering, Python, R, SQL, Julia.
2017-23	ML RESEARCHER UNITED NATIONS (ITU), GENEVA Researcher; Machine Learning, Built Homomorphic Encryption (Python, R, Julia) library. Developed AWS (Kubernetes/Docker) transcript and translation platform, trained custom SageMaker models. Built Flask web app for QR codes of itu.int domains. Android (Java/Kotlin) and iOS apps.
2016-17	RESEARCHER UNITED NATIONS (UNCTAD), GENEVA Impact evaluation of FTAs on Developing Countries (East African Community), using Computation General Equilibrium programming (GTAP)
2015–16	ECONOMIST THE INTERNET SOCIETY, GENEVA Paper on exogenous increase in availability of local language content and internet adoption, presented at EEA 2016 Conceputalised and executed report "Promoting Local Content in Africa" presented at Africa Internet Summit, leading to Google update advertising policy to help monetise African language content. Global Latency measurements (Dyn).
2013-15	RESEARCH CONSULTANT COGINTA, GENEVA / GUINEA Directed a large scale representative baseline survey of Conakry (Guinea) population Conducted analysis for Canton of Geneva commissioned survey on police victimisation
2014–15	RESEARCH ASSISTANT CENTRE ON CONFLICT, DEVELOPMENT AND PEACEBUILDING Collaborated with the "Institute Nationale du Development Humaine" (govt. Morocco) to supervise 400-household sruvey, using RDD identification strategy
2013-14	RESEARCH ASSISTANT CENTRE FOR FINANCE AND DEVELOPMENT, GENEVA Developed survey design on remittances from Geneva Redeveloped Centre's website
2013-14	TEACHING ASSISTANT THE GRADUATE INSTITUTE, GENEVA Taught weekly Masters' Statistics workshops Supervised Masters' Research Projects
2012	RESEARCH CONSULTANT DUTCH DEVELOPMENT FINANCE INSTITUTE FMO, THE HAGUE Designed and directed survey on ESG funds performance
2009	RESEARCH ASSISTANT UNIVERSITY OF GRONINGEN, NETHERLANDS Data collection and analysis for Ministry of Economics Affairs commissioned survey

Education

2012–16 PHD IN DEVELOPMENT ECONOMICS | THE GRADUATE INSTITUTE GENEVA

Jury: Richard Baldwin (president), Jean-Louis Arcand (supervisor) & Michael Kende

Internet Adoption in Africa | Trade & Global Value Chains | Gender and Child Growth

2010–12	Research for Dr. Piedro Veglio, Executive Director of the World Bank Microhydropower in remote dev. countries, at the World Bank (D.C.)
2006-10	BSC ECONOMICS UNIVERSITY OF GRONINGEN
2006-10	BA THEORETICAL PHILOSOPHY UNIVERSITY OF GRONINGEN

Software experience

Python (Tensorflow, PyTorch), R, Julia, SQL, C, Go, Rust Javascript, Swift, Linux, LaTeX Selected Research Papers

2017	"Global Value Chains in LICs" CTEI Working Paper Series
2016	"Making the Next Billion Demand Access" CFD Working Paper G7 briefing notes
2015	"decompr: GVC decomposition in R" CTEI Working Paper Series

Conference Presentations

2016	The Internet Adoption from google.co.za in Setswana" EEA Annual Conference 2016
2013	"Urban Violence and Collective Efficacy in Karachi and Dhaka" Pictet Foundation

Other Publications, Op Eds and Short Notes

2017 "Global Value Chains in Developing Economies" | *VoxEU*

Software Development

2023	HEtools PyPI. Homomorphic Encryption (BFV, BGV, CKKS).
2023	HEtools Julia General Registery. Homomorphic Encryption (BFV, BGV, CKKS).
2023	HomomorphicEncryption CRAN. Homomorphic Encryption (BFV, BGV, CKKS).
2023	libactication <i>PyPI</i> . Activation functions (sigmoid, logistic, Gompertz, ReLU).
2022	transformer CRAN. transformer blocks (attention, feed-forward neural networks).
2016	rnn CRAN. Recurrent Neural Network architectures in native R.
2016	datasets.load CRAN. utilities and Graphical User Interface for loading datasets 130k
2015	decompr CRAN. Global Value Chain decomposition.
2014	diagonals CRAN. Tools for manipulating fat-diagonal matrices, e.g. block matrices

Languages

English (native), Dutch (native), Spanish (advanced), German (advanced), French (advanced)

Affiliations

Ifo Economists Expert Group (University of Munich, for Switzerland)